ENRIQUE HERREROS

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Toronto, Canada

PHONE

+1-437-989-8623

EMAIL

eherrerosj@gmail.com

DATE OF BIRTH

May-1990

NATIONALITY

Spanish & Canadian

SOCIAL

eherreros.com

LinkedIn

Twitter

Medium

SKILLS

Python

Machine Learning, Deep Learning

Django

Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Keras / PyTorch

SQL

Docker

Pandas / Sklearn / Numpy

Kubernetes

Linux

LANGUAGES

English: mother tongue Spanish: mother tongue

HOBBIES

Squash, tennis, kitesurf, biking, swimming, reading and cinema

PROFILE

7+ years experienced Software / ML Engineer with proven success in building and deploying software, especially ML-related. Currently fully immersed in the crypto world. Passionate, curious and quick-learner, I bring experience from small, medium and large companies, which taught me to quickly zoom in from the whole picture to low-level details. I thrive when immersed in high-skilled technical teams.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

August 2021 - Today Toronto

Electric Capital

Developing and analyzing crypto things.

Stack: Python, Google Cloud

CTO & Co-Founder

April 2019 - June 2021 Barcelona

Shalion

Co-Founded Shalion, a web SaaS that helps top-tier brands monitor their ecommerce performance. Developed from scratch and deployed the backend, machine learning algorithms, web scrapers and infrastructure of all 3 products. Hired and led a team of developers, which were key to grow from 0 to 500K€ ARR and from 3 to 20 employees in

Stack: Python, AWS, Django REST, Scrapy, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Sentry, sklearn Feb 2018 - Sept 2019

Machine Learning Engineer & Co-Founder

Madrid

Xplore.ai

Co-Founded Xplore.ai, a ML consultancy company. I engineered and deployed ML and Deep Learning solutions for clients like BBVA, Mango, FindHotel or Smart Protection, allowing the company to grow from 0 to +150K€ revenue in the first year. Was accepted at Telefónica Open Future startup incubator. Spin-off into Shalion.

Stack: Python, Keras, PyTorch, AWS, Docker, Flask, SQL

Jan 2017 - June 2018 Amsterdam

Machine Learning Engineer

FindHotel

Built the main ML algorithms from scratch for a hotel booking marketplace with +150K customers/month. Developed: (1) hotel recommender, which significantly increased conversions; (2) booking cancellation prediction model, (3) price prediction model, that was key for inventory reselling.

Stack: XGBoost, Random Forest, kNN, KD-Tree. Prod: AWS Batch, API Gateway, Docker and Jenkins June 2014 - Sept 2016

Madrid

Data Scientist

Deloitte

Consultated a large insurance company in Spain in IT risks projects. Developed ad-hoc fraud detection and prevention tools and models that allowed fraud reduction by +3MM€. Stack: Python, scikit-learn, Splunk, SQL, jQuery

EDUCATION

<u>University of Amsterdam</u>

MSc. Data Science, CUM LAUDE

Sept 2016 - Sept 2017

Amsterdam

Thesis: "Hotel Booking Cancellation Modeling using ML"

BSc. Communication Systems Engineering

Universidad Carlos III de Madrid

Sept 2008 - Dec 2013 Madrid

Thesis passed with distinction: "Platform for Analysis, Monitoring and Web Visualization of 802.11 Traffic"